<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>dpeter99's blog</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on dpeter99's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.148.0</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 09:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dpeter99.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shadow engine ECS Part 1</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2025-07-13-shdow-ecs-par-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2025-07-13-shdow-ecs-par-1/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="rethinking-entity-component-systems-a-graph-based-approach">Rethinking Entity-Component Systems: A Graph-Based Approach&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>When building a game engine from scratch, one of the most fundamental decisions you&amp;rsquo;ll make is how to represent and manage your game world. The Entity-Component-System (ECS) pattern has become the gold standard for many modern engines, but after working with various implementations, I&amp;rsquo;ve started to question whether the traditional approach is always the best fit for every game.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this series, I&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring a different take on ECS design—one that borrows concepts from graph theory to create a more flexible and intuitive system for game developers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Game engine logic systems</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2022-02-26-game-io-logic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 17:55:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2022-02-26-game-io-logic/</guid><description>Small exploration of game event systems for a University project</description></item><item><title>Forge 1.18 update</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/forge/forge_118/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 01:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/forge/forge_118/</guid><description>&lt;p>For anyone asking for 1.18 forge here is the rundown of the process that goes into updating it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: warning
&lt;strong>For players&lt;/strong>
There are builds of forge available, these currently have bugs but need testing.
If you have the time please try them out and report any bugs you find in discord.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Mods that work with 1.18.1 do not automatically mean they work with 1.18.2
This means that modders need to update their mods individually, and the update may take time, even after forge is done.
:::&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forge 1.17 update</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/forge/forge_117/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 14:35:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/forge/forge_117/</guid><description>&lt;p>For anyone asking for 1.17 forge here is the rundown of the process that goes into updating it.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[!WARNING]
Forge for this version is no longer supported.
If you are a mod developer please try to update your mods to 1.18 as soon as possible.&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This version only recieved a recommended build before dropping the support. This was due to the large number of changes that happend in MC code and in Forge&amp;rsquo;s code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Broken SSD</title><link>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2021-07-08-broken_ssd/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 09:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dpeter99.github.io/posts/2021-07-08-broken_ssd/</guid><description>&lt;h4 id="tldr">TL;DR&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Soo on 07.04 my SSD broke down. But it wasn&amp;rsquo;t an easy case of windows telling me that it went bad and I had to spend the better pat of a day diagnosing the problem.
In the end I had to get a new one.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-error">The error&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I was using Windows just as any other day, and while leaving it to go eat, it broke. What I got back for was a normal Win logon screen but the background was just green (my accent color in windows).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>